Inventory of the Maupin-Washington Papers 1732-1932
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Maupin-Washington Papers, 1732-1932.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 65 M44
271 items.
Papers, 1732-1932, of the Maupin and Washington families.
Chapman Maupin,; Socrates Maupin,; Peter Grayson Washington.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 271 items, 07/27/1951.
Biographical/Historical Information
Biography to be added later.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1732-1932, of the Maupin and Washington families. The bulk of the papers, 1850-1870, are letters received by Peter Grayson Washington who served as Assistant Secretary of the U. S. Treasury from 1853- 1857. Most of the letters relate to political patronage, Democratic Party politics and the various responsibilities of the Treasury Department. Later letters relate to Washington's work as a claims agent in Washington, D. C. and to his investments in New York City.
The collection also includes letters written to Socrates Maupin (1809-1871), professor of medicine at the University of Virginia, including letters to him and correspondence of his son Chapman Maupin (1846- 1900), during the American Civil War and while studying in Europe. Letters and ephemera relating to Chapman Maupin's interest in his Washington forbearers are included as well. There are also land records, autographs and a carte-de-visite of Edwin Booth.
Arrangement
Organization
This collection is organized into five series. Series 1 contains the personal and business correspondence of Peter Grayson Washington; Series 2 contains correspondence of the Maupin family; Series 3 contains genealogical information; Series 4 contains deeds and other items relating to the exchange of land; Series 5 contains miscellaneous material; Series 6 contains photographs.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically by date within each series. Series 1 is divided into subseries by years.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Maupin family.; Washington family.
Persons:
Booth, Edwin, 1833- 1893.; Maupin, Chapman, 1846-1900.; Maupin, Socrates, 1808-1871.
Subjects:
United States. Dept. of the Treasury.
Components List
  Series 1: Personal and Business Correspondence of Peter Grayson Washington
- Personal and Business Correspondence of Peter Grayson Washington, 1835-1866, n.d. (Box 1-2)
  - Personal and Business Correspondence, 1835-1852. (Box-folder 1:1-2)
    - Jno. Coffee, House [of] Representatives, [Washington, D.C.], to Rev. O. B. Brown, Pay Office, 2 January 1835., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Sends a letter from Silas S. Boggess on his pay for transporting the mail. In pencil, notations on sums due in 1834.
    - James M. Buchanan, Balt[imore, Maryland], to [?], 2 December 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Invites recipient to join Mr. Yancey and a few friends from Washington for dinner.
    - Geo[rge] M. Brooke, B[reve]t Brig[a]d[ier] Gen[era]l, Head Qu[arte]rs, First Division, New Orleans, [Louisiana], to Caption Charles Clark, 2d Mississippi Rifles, New Orleans, Louisiana, 18 August 1847., 2 pages. LS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Orders Clark to embark his detachment of recruits for Brazos, N. Iago, and from there, go to Matamoros and report to Col. W[illia]m Davenport.
      This letter was included with the letter listed below; William Davenport to Charles Clark, 3 September 1847.
    - Note on verso from W[illia]m Davenport, Col. Matamoros, [Mexico], to Charles Clark, 3 September 1847., 2 pages. ANS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Ordering Capt. Clark and his detachment to headquarters beyond Monterey.
      This letter was included within the above letter; George M. Brooke to Captin Charles Clark, 18 August 1847.
    - J[oseph] R[eed] Ingersoll, Washington, [D.C.], to Tho[ma]s Carbury, Washington, [D.C.], 22 December 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Forwarded Mr. Pettrich's petition to the Committee on Buildings and Grounds; some person more familiar with the circumstances should see Mr. J. W. Houston.
    - David S[ettle] Reid, House [of] Representatives, Washington, [D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, Aud[itor] for P[ost] O[ffice] Dep[artmen]t, Washington, [D.C.], 8 May 1848., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Requests return of papers sent in the case of Whitman.
    - A[braham] R[obinson] McIlvaine, H[ouse of] Rep[resentative]s, [Washington, D.C.], to Mr. [Peter Grayson] Washington, n.p., 6 July [18]48., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Asks Washington to send him a reply so he can answer a letter from Mr. [Charles B.] Penrose.
    - Abraham R[obinson] McIlvaine, House [of] Rep[resentative]s, [Washington, D.C.], to P. D.[sic][G.] Washington, n.p., 18 July [18]48., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Has received a letter from Mr. [Charles B.] Penrose who has not yet received the draft, though Penrose sent the required deposition.
    - J. M. Mason, Senate Chamber, [Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 9 January [18]50., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Inquires about the claim of Mr. Pagnall of Norfolk, [Virginia], for his examination of the Carter and Roddy claims.
    - John Cadwalader, Philad[elphi]a, [Pennsylvania], to Peter Grayson Washington, Washington, D.C., 13 February 1850, 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Discusses information on a patent issued to James Rumsey for a reaction wheel with a fixed flume, and one to James Macombe for a horizontal hollow water wheel.
    - John Cadwalader, Philad[elphi]a, [Pennsylvania], to Peter Grayson Washington, Washington, D.C., 13 February 1850, 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      More information on the Rumsey patent.
    - W[illiam] Medill, Convention Chamber, Columbus, Ohio, to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 4 June 1850., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Is very busy as president of the Convention; sends his best wishes to Mrs. Washington, and Miss Virginia.
    - Cha[rle]s Clark, Fayette, [Mississippi] to "Dear Sir," n.p., 24 August 1850., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Sends a draft; politics are very quiet since everyone is concentrating on the cotton cropage.
    - R[ichard] H[enry] Stanton, Maysville, Kentucky, to Col. Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 6 June 1851., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Will find a safe bearer for a letter to a young lady in Louisville; discusses his Whig opponent, W[illia]m C. Marshall, and the approaching campaign.
    - R[ichard] H[enry] Stanton, Maysville, Kentucky, to [Peter Grayson Washington], n.p., 19 June 1851., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Is busy campaigning.
    - Cha[rle]s Clark, Fayette, [Mississippi], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 28 October 1851, 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Received the land warrants for himself and Capt. Coffee [?]; Foote will be elected governor over Davis.
    - Certificate of the Officers and Board of Managers of the Washington National Monument Society, showing a picture of the proposed monument and giving 19 signatures, including those of Millard Fillmore, Tho[mas] Carbery, and Winfield Scott, M[atthew] F[ontaine] Maury, and Peter Force. Facsimile, 1 August 1852., 1 page. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Geo[rge] H. Duley, Lt., Top[ographical] Engineers, Medfield, Massachusetts, to Col. Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 29 October 1852., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Requests Washington's help in preventing the removal of Charles Onion as Post Master at Medfield.
  - Personal and Business Correspondence, 1853, [1853-1857]. (Box-folder 1:3-4)
    - R[ichard] W[iggington] Thompson, Brown's Hotel, [Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 5 March [1853-1857], 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Asks for word when the President [Pierce]'s order about his business reaches the Treasury Department.
    - Tazewell Taylor, Norfolk, [Virginia], to Peter Grayson Washington, Assistant Secretary [of the] Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], 10 March 1853., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Congratulates Washington on his new office; introduces Walter H. Taylor of Norfolk, Superintendent of the New Customs House Building, who Taylor hopes will keep his position.
    - Jno. Milledge, Augusta, [Georgia], to "My Dear Sir" [Peter Grayson Washington], n.p., 16 March 1853., 5 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Congratulates Washington on his new position; praises the new President [Pierce] and his foreign policy; feels sectional rivalries will dissipate; asks that W[illia]m B. Hall be retained as their Postmaster.
    - Myra Clark Gaines, Washington, D.C., to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 16 March [18]53., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Recommends Edward White for an appraisership at San Francisco.
    - O. S. Dickenson, Binghampton, [New York], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 17 March [18]53., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Congratulates Washington on his new position.
    - A[usburn] Birdsall, Washington, [D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 19 March 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Asks assistance in getting the appointment of Superintendent of Light Houses on the Hudson River for Joseph O. Hasbrouck.
    - Charles Sweetser, Delaware, Ohio, to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 6 April 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Expresses his pleasure at Washington's appointment.
    - Smith Pyne, [Washington, D.C.?], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 16 April [1853-1857]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Introduces someone who wants a position in the Department [of the Treasury].
    - Robert Dale Owen, Philadelphia, [Pennsylvania], to Peter Washington, [Washington, D.C.], 20 April 1853., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Asks Washington to give Mr. Guthrie an enclosed letter.
    - Lew[is] Cass, Detroit, [Michigan], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 22 April 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Introduces Mr. Watson [?].
    - R[obert] M[ercer] T[aliaferro] Hunter, n.p., to Peter Grayson Washington, [Washington, D.C.], April 1853., 1 page. ANS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Introduces Taliaferro Hunter of Fredericksburg, [Virginia], who is to be appointed chief clerk to the Light House Board.
    - Jno. Milledge, n.p., to [Peter Grayson Washington?], n.p., 14 May 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Discusses papers regarding certain bounty land claims given Mr. Edwards by the recipient.
    - A[usburn] Birdsall, Binghampton, [New York], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 16 May [1853-1857]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Inquires about appointments under the Treasury Department.
    - Joseph Henry, Smithsonian Inst[itution, Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, Treasury Depart[ment, Washington, D.C.], 18 May 1853., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Introduces Gen. Brisbane of South Carolina, who wishes to discuss some matters with Washington.
    - J[ohn] L. O'Sullivan, Willard's [Hotel, Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, Assistant Secretary of the Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], 24 May 1853., 1 page. ANS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Encloses a letter Washington suggested he [O'Sullivan] write, and asks that Washington look at the application at once.
    - Cha[rle]s G. Greene, Boston, [Massachusetts], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 25 May [1853-1857?]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Introduce Mr. Amos Stevens, a skillful mechanic who has devised improvements in balances and scales for weighing.
    - George D[ennison] Prentice, Louisville, [Kentucky], to [Peter Grayson] Washington, n.p., 18 June [1853-1857]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Asks that his brother, a clerk in the Treasury Department, not lose his position; publishes a partisan newspaper, but during Taylor and Fillmore administrations, was able to prevent the removal of many Democrats.
    - T[homas] J.D. Fuller, Calais, Maine, to Peter Grayson Washington, [Washington], D.C., 25 June 1853., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Asks for Washington's assistance in keeping the "cutter" in the "6th District"; encourages Washington to make a personal inspection.
    - Tho[ma]s ap C. Jones, "near Prospect Hill [Fairfax County], Virginia, to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 30 June 1853., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Reminds him of an invitation to make a personal inspection.
    - Dan[ie]l Mace Lafayette, Indiana, to Peter Grayson Washington, Ass[istan]t Treasurer, [Washington, D.C.], 10 July 1853., 1 page. ANS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Introduces N. L. Carr who has a clerkship "in your dept."
    - James L. Orr, Anderson, [South Carolina] to Peter Grayson Washington, [Washington, D.C.], 20 July 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Introduces Alexander S[tuart] Wallace"a member of our State Legislature."
    - Edson B. Olds, Philadelphia, [Pennsylvania], to Peter Grayson Washington, Ass[istan]t Sec[retary of the] Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], 24 July 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Discusses the situation of Parker "of the Chillicothe District" and his chance for a clerkship.
    - James G. Brent[?], Washington, [D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 25 July 1853., 1 page. ANS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Introduces Mr. Joseph Jerwith of Alexandria, Virginia.
    - A[ngel] Calderon de la Barca, n.p., to Peter Grayson Washington, Assistant Secretary of the Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], 29 July 1853., 1 page. ANS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Encloses a bill of lading for "sweet-meats" from Havana; would like Washington to order their free delivery in New York.
    - J[ohn] W[ien] Forney, Washington, [D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 16 August 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Introduces J. C. McKubbin[?] of California.
    - John Tyler, Jr., 46th South 6 Street, Philadelphia, [Pennsylvania], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 24 Aug [18]53., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Asks if position of [Treasury Department] Librarian, vacated due to the death of Mr. Taliaferro, has been filled, the salary, and whether Washington could keep it open for a few days. Endorsed as answered 25 August 1853.
    - J[ohn] C[adwalader], Saratoga Springs, [New York], to Peter Grayson Washington, Washington, D.C., 27 August 1853., 20 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Discusses objects of current interest - the funding of the Pacific Railroad, and Cuba.
    - Spencer F. Baird, Ass[istan]t Sec[retary], Smithsonian I[nstitution, Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, Ass[istan]t Secretary [of the] Treasury, Washington, [D.C.], 25 October 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Encloses a letter to be forwarded to Capt. W. C. Pease, with suggestions on making collections in natural history; asks if Mr. Charles Cavileer, who has been making meteorological observations, is still collector of customs at Pembina, Minnesota.
    - T. L. Smith, n.p. to Col. [?], n.p., 1 November [18]53., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Invites recipient to a family dinner to "test some old wine."
    - [Caleb] Cushing, Att[orne]y Gen[era]l's Off[ice], [Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 1 December 1853., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Asks Washington to ask Secretary [Guthrie] to postpone the nomination of an inspector in the place of G. J. L. Colby.
    - Ro[bert] Tyler, Phila[delphia, Pennsylvania] to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 10 December [18]53., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Praises Mr. Guthrie's Report; defended Guthrie during the recent denunciations; feels Guthrie's detractors were speculators, from New York and elsewhere, who want a more pliant Secretary.
    - J[ohn] L. O'Sullivan, New York, [New York], to Peter Grayson Washington, Ass[istan]t Sec[retar]y of [the] Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], 29 December 1853., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Sends some additional figures for a form sent to Mr. Guthrie in an earlier mail; discusses the precedents for Washington's appointment.
    - H[enry] May, n.p., to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 29 December 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Apologizes for letting out news of a wage increase for Customs House employees.
    - John Slidell, Washington, [D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 30 December 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Asks that Lieutenant Richmond not have to serve on the Mobile, [Alabama] Station.
    - Jon Cadwalader, n.p. to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., [1853-1857]., 2 pages. LS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Discusses Mr. Yost's declining of an appointment; will suggest someone else for the position.
    - R[ose] O'N[eal] Greenhow, "H Street between 15 and 16", [Washington, D.C?], to [Peter Grayson] Washington, Assistant Sec[retary] of [the] Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], [1853-1857]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Needs the duplicate of the draft for $1,000.
    - W[illia]m B. Hodge, n.p. to [Peter Grayson Washington], n.p., [1853-1857]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Asks that a warrant to Mr. Aspinwall be given to Mr. G[uthrie] for his signature.
    - Dan[ie]l Mace, n.p. to Peter Grayson Washington, Asst[istant] Treasurer, n.p., [1853-1857]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Hopes Mr. Parr will pass the examination for a third class clerkship.
    - A. Smith, n.p., to Col. Peter Grayson W[ashington], n.p., [1853-1857]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Asks for a position in California for his wife's brother, John.
    - J. Knox Walker, [Washington, D.C.], to [Peter Grayson?] Washington, n.p., [1853-1857]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Reports that Mr. Sam[ue]l Whithorne, about whom the President [Pierce] spoke this morning, is unwell and not able to begin his duties.
    - Sidney Webster, [Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., [1853-1857]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Asks for employment for John McMahon.
    - Sidney Webster, [Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., [1853-1857]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Reports that, at the President's [Pierce] direction, wrote the Collector at Eastport, Maine that Mr. Andrews should keep his job.
  - Personal and Business Correspondence, 1854. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - H[arry] Hibbard, Gadslyn[?], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 9 January 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Introduces Gen. Lamprey of Hampton, New Hampshire.
    - S[tephen] R[ussell] Mallory, n.p. to Col. [Peter Grayson] Washington, n.p., 10 January [18]54., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Introduces Th[omas?] Blount, who has applied for a clerkship.
    - Jos[eph] R[ipley] Chandler, House of Representatives, Washington, [D.C], to Peter Grayson Washington, Ass[istant] Sec[retary] of the Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], 13 January 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Asks about the use of nickel in coins, and for a reply to his questions on the Smithsonian Funds.
    - W[illia]m Smith, Washington, [D.C], to "My dear Sir," n.p., 13 January 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Regrets his absence when the bill on the Assistant Secretary of the Treasury was rejected.
    - C[harles] C. Jewett, Smithsonian Institution, [Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 19 January 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Introduces Charles B. Norton of New York, a publisher and bookseller who wants to discuss duties on books.
    - John M. Read, Philadelphia, [Pennsylvania], to Peter Grayson Washington, Ass[istan]t Sec[retary] of the Treasury, Washington, [D.C.], 27 January 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Asks Washington to call the Secretary of the Treasury's attention to a letter from Messrs. Powers and Weightman[?] on duty-free manufactured articles.
    - M[atthew] Birchard, House of Representatives, Columbus, Ohio, to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 30 January [18]54., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Asks for assistance in getting a better position for his brother-in-law, William Weaver.
    - H[enry] May, n.p., to Col. Peter Grayson Washington, Ass[istan]t Sec[retary] of [the] Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], 31 January [18]54., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Encloses a letter from his constituent, Major George; discusses the Collector, George[?] Thomas, and a position for Col. [Tench] Tilgham of the Eastern Shore.
    - Cha[rle]s G. Greene, Boston, [Massachusetts], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 7 February [18]54., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Introduces R. S. S. Andros, Deputy Collector at Boston.
    - Th[?] Walsh, Secretary, Army and Navy Club, [Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 14 March 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Forwards a resolution [enclosed] of the Annual General Meeting of the Army and Navy Club, thanking Washington for a volume of statistical information.
    - M[ilton] S[locum] Latham, House of Representatives, Washington, [D.C], to James Guthrie, Sec[retary] of [the] Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], 11 April [18]54., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Encloses communication from Dr. Birdsall, Superintendent of the Mint in California.
    - James Ross Snowden, Director, Mint of the United States, Philadelphia, [Pennsylvania], to Peter Grayson Washington, Acting Sec[retary] of the Treasury, Washington City [D.C.], 1 May 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Plans to come to Washington to meet with him in 2 days.
    - W. F. Allen, [Olney?], New York to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 4 May 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Introduces Tho[mas] H. Bond, who wants a leave of absence for his son, John G. Bond, of the Reserve Marines.
    - A[ndrew] Stevenson, Blenheim, Carter's Bridge P[os]t Off[ice], Albemarle [County, Virginia], to P. Washington, n.p., 24 June 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Understands Congress has approved paying expenses of the Springfield Commission, of which he was a member.
    - Jno. Nelson, Balt[im]o[re], [Maryland], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 10 July 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Asks for assistance in keeping Edgar Irving as Inspector in the Customs House in New York.
    - J[ohn] Ross Browne, San Francisco, California, to Peter Grayson Washington, Ass[istan]t Secretary of the Treasury, [Washington, D.C.], 15 July [18]54., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Feels there is too much electioneering in California, and that it harms the Democratic Party.
    - Gerrit Smith, House of Representatives, [Washington, D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 17 July 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Has received Washington's note; does not know if Janet[?] Richardson is in Washington.
    - Charles W. Upham, House of Representatives, Washington City [D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 17 July 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Asks that necessary information be sent to Senator [R. M. T.] Hunter to secure an appropriation to repair a Customs House.
    - W. Meade Addison, Baltimore, [Maryland], to Peter Grayson Washington, Washington, [D.C.], 27 July 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Regarding Mrs. Allison and a Paymastership[?]; feels the Chief Justice recognizes a lasting obligation to Washington and Mr. Guthrie; settlement of the suit will cheer the Chief Justice's "last days of his useful life."
    - Charles W. Upham, House of Representatives, Washington City [D.C.], to Peter Grayson Washington, n.p., 2 August 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Regarding tactics to get an appropriation to save a building.
    - Emile Lasere, New Orleans, [Louisiana], to Peter Grayson Washington, Assistant Sec[retary] of the Treasury, Washington, D.C., 13 September 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)
      Introduces Dennis Cronan[?].
    - T[homas] J[ames] D[uncan] Fuller, Calais, [Maine], to Peter Grayson Washington, Washington, [D.C.], 21 September 1854., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:5)